# **Erick Meline**



erickmeline@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/erick-m-2943819



925-451-1168



https://ericks-portfolio4.herokuapp.com

## Summary

I'm a creative problem-solver with a versatile and diverse skill set as a Web Developer with an eye for design. Drawing on a breadth of coding and software development experience, I seek to outperform and build on innovation, utilizing both creativity and programming expertise. I hold professional certificates in Full Stack Web Development from the University of California Berkeley, and Front-end Application Development from Codecademy. I enjoy bringing creativity and technical skills to a company where I can grow and become a valuable asset.

### **Experience**



#### Front-end Web Developer

Sierra Club

Mar 2015 - Present (6 years 5 months +)

Managed Sierra Club's addup.org Web Application, which included creating new features, modifying existing features, and bug fixes. Tech was mostly vanilla javascript and React. Liaised with third party vendor that built the site. Integrated customized features using Salesforce apis for data management. Conducted various A/B testing using Optimizely testing suite.

### **Senior Front-end Developer**

**GE Software** 

Oct 2013 - Nov 2014 (1 year 2 months)

Developed single page application modules in angular and plain old javascript. Provided team expertise in front-end html/css semantics and responsive design fundamentals. Also had projects that used Bootstrap, HTML5 Canvas, and High Charts. Used Jasmine testing framework and Karma to perform js unit testing.

# Senior Front-end Developer

Expedia Group

Jun 2011 - Oct 2013 (2 years 5 months)

Collaborated with back-end developers, and UX/designers to provide the front-end development of HTML, Javascript, and JSTL for new and updated application features for both desktop and mobile sites. Proposed and architected a mobile-first responsive HTML5 and CSS3 methodology with a focus on website performance optimization.



#### Lead Front-end Developer

1up.com, Hearst Media

Aug 2006 - Apr 2011 (4 years 9 months)

Hand-coding of HTML, Javascript and JSTL within the JSP layer using Eclipse with CVS. Updated legacy is with iQuery framework. Managed a small production team of Associate Web Producers to deliver daily website content, updates, landing pages, promotions, and emails. Converted the sites'

hundreds of table-based HTML layout JSPs to more modular design pattern using valid semantic tableless xhtml and valid css.

#### Website Architect

MarkMonitor/Alldomains.com;

Feb 2000 - Apr 2006 (6 years 3 months)

Responsible for front-end development of www.markmonitor, alldomains.com and allwhois.com as well as the internal corporate intranet. Primary duties included HTML, and programming in Perl & Javascript, email campaigns, and marketing deliverables. Liaison between Marketing and Engineering. I began this position with Alldomains.com which was acquired by MarkMonitor in 2003.

#### **Education**



### University of California, Berkeley

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development Mar 2021 - Jun 2021

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



**Building Front-End Web React Apps** - Codecademy

https://www.credential.net/19801042-2756-4bff-880a-a25ad45038fe#gs.4nnq8y

#### **Skills**

JavaScript • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • React.js • jQuery • Node.js • ECMAScript • Express.js • JSON • Responsive Web Design